## Prince Sandhu. Jarvis Consulting

I have graduated with a Bachelor's in Software Engineering from McMaster University in 2019. I am currently employed by Jarvis Consulting Group in pursuit of extensively expanding my software application skills through working on various exciting projects by utilizing current and in-demand technologies and frameworks. My prior industry experience includes a one-year internship at the Ontario Ministry of Children, Community and Social Services. I supported the System Development & Maintenance team in planning, developing, implementing, and testing the Child Protection Information Network (CPIN) application, along with providing tier-2 support for onboarding regional agencies. I particularly enjoy tackling new challenges regularly and the dynamic nature of the profession is what excites me and is precisely the reason why I chose to pursue a career in the software development industry.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, Algorithms & Data Structures, Linux/Bash, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: C, JavaScript, RDBMS/SQL, HTML/CSS, React Native

Familiar: TypeScript, React, Python, JUnit, MATLAB, UML

### Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_PrinceSandhu

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: ...

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- JDBC App: ...
- Grep App: ...

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

# **Highlighted Projects**

| <b></b> : |  |
|-----------|--|
| <b></b> : |  |

### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (December 2021-present): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

Junior Application Developer, Ontario Ministry of Children, Community, and Social Services (September 2017-September 2018): Supported the System Development & Maintenance team in planning, developing, implementing, and testing the Child Protection Information Network application. Documented and tracked testing defects, debugged, and troubleshot to ensure new requirements are implemented while existing functionality is not compromised.

### Education

McMaster University (2014-2019), Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering - Dean's List (2017,2019) - GPA: 3.5/4.0

## Miscellaneous

- Harvard edX Mobile App Development with React Native (2020)
- Laguages: English, Punjabi, French
- Day-trading
- Volleyball, baseball, basketball, tennis, and hockey player
- Cycling
- Bhangra Dancer
- Maple Leafs, Blue Jays, Raptors, UFC fan